deitel.com 2006-10-18

# Deitel & Associates, Inc. Privacy Statement

Deitel® Buzz Online   
free e-mail newsletter  
Register Now!

| | 

**Privacy Statement of Deitel & Associates, Inc. **   

**

**Information about our Organization and Web site**

**

Modern information and communication technologies play a fundamental role in the activities of an organization like Deitel & Associates, Inc. . We are based in USA .  Our principal activities are: 

  * Computer Science Authors 
  * Corporate Training 

Our privacy policy covers Deitel & Associates, Inc. and its Web site: 

** |  Organization Name:  |  Deitel & Associates, Inc.   
---|---  
Address:  |  5 Clock Tower Place, Suite 450   
City, Zip:  |  Maynard  ,  01754   
State:  |  MA   
Country:  |  USA   
Controller:  |  Deitel & Associates, Inc.   
Web Sites(s):  |  www.deitel.com   
**

** **Providing Visitors with Anonymous Access** **   

You can access our Web site home page and browse our site without disclosing your personal data. 

** ** The services and links of our Web site  ** **   

Our Web site enables you to communicate with other visitors or to post information to be accessed by others. When you do so, other visitors may collect your data. 

Our Web site does not include links to third party Web service providers. 

** Automatic Collection of Information  **   

We automatically log personal data by means such as programming or we link information automatically logged by such means with personal data about specific individuals. We do so for the following purposes: 

  * Technical administration of the Web site 
  * Customer administration 
  * Marketing 
  * Keeping basic statistics on the files our readers download from our site. 

We use cookies to store personal data or we link information stored in cookies with personal data about specific individuals. We do so for the following purposes: 

  * Customer administration 
  * Marketing 
  * To ensure that a user is registered before allowing the user to download files from our site. 

** Data Collection and Purpose Specification  **   

We collect the personal data that you may volunteer while using our services. 

We do not collect information about our visitors from other sources, such as public records or bodies, or private organizations. 

To access the table of personal data collected and purposes for which they are used, please  click here 

We do not collect or use personal data for any purpose other than that indicated in the table below. 

If we wish to use your personal data for new purposes, we offer you the means to consent to those new purposes: 

  * by indicating in a box at the point on the site where personal data is collected 
  * by sending an email ( deitel@deitel.com ) 
  * by visiting this url ( http://www.deitel.com ) 

** Children's Privacy  **   

We do not knowingly collect personal data from children. 

We do not take specific steps to protect the privacy of children who disclose their personal data to us. 

We do provide information about our personal data practices in relation to children on our home page and wherever we knowingly collect personnal data from children on our Web site. 

** Disclosure and Visitor Choice  **   

We disclose our visitors' personal data to our subsidiaries or other organizations. 

Where we disclose your personal data for the same purposes as those indicated in the table below, we provide you with the means to  opt-in to disclosure:  opt-out of disclosure: 

  * by indicating in a box at the point on the site where personal data is collected 
  * by sending an email ( deitel@deitel.com ) 
  * by visiting this url ( http://www.deitel.com ) 

Where we disclose your personal data for purposes which are different from those indicated in the table mentioned above, we offer you the opportunity to consent to disclosure: 

  * by indicating in a box at the point on the site where personal data is collected 
  * by sending an email ( deitel@deitel.com ) 
  * by visiting this url ( http://www.deitel.com ) 

** Confidentiality / Security  **   

We do not give visitors to our Web site the option of using a secure transmission method to send us their personal data. 

We have implemented security policies, rules and technical measures to protect the personal data that we have under our control from: 

  * unauthorized access 
  * improper use or disclosure 
  * unauthorized modification 
  * unlawful destruction or accidental loss 

All our employees and data processors, who have access to, and are associated with the processing of personal data, are obliged to respect the confidentiality of our visitors' personal data. 

We ensure that your personal data will not be disclosed to State institutions and authorities except if required by law or other regulation. 

** Access to the personal data we may hold about you  **   

You can ask us, by: 

  * sending an email ( deitel@deitel.com ) 
  * By the fact that they must register to download our materials. 

whether we are keeping personal data about you. 

Upon request, which you can indicate by: 

  * sending an email ( deitel@deitel.com ) 

We will provide you with a readable copy of the personal data which we keep about you,  within a week.  \- although we may before require proof of your identity -.  We will provide the information  without any charge. 

We allow you to challenge the data that we hold about you and, where appropriate, you may have the data: 

  * erased 
  * rectified or amended 
  * completed 

We reserve the right to refuse to provide our visitors with a copy of their personal data,  but will give reasons for our refusal. 

We do, however, allow you to challenge our decision to refuse to provide you with a copy of your personal data. 

** Privacy Compliance  **   

Our privacy policy is compliant with the following instrument:  Self-Assessment Procedure 

There are no global or regional regulatory or self-regulatory schemes applicable to our web site or organization. 

In order to demonstrate that our privacy policy accords with the above privacy  instrument,  we are: 

  * voluntarily committed to a Self Assessment procedure 

####  Self Assessment procedure 

Name or designation of the privacy policy person or service  |  Deitel & Associates, Inc.   
---|---  
URL  |  http://www.deitel.com   
Address  |  5 Clock Tower Place, Suite 450, Maynard, MA 01754   
Country  |  USA   

####  Primary personal data/Business information 

**x** |  volunteered by each visitor   
---|---  
\-  |  collected from public records or bodies   
\-  |  collected from private organizations   
  
####  Other personal details and profiling data 

\-  |  volunteered by each visitor   
---|---  
\-  |  collected from public records or bodies   
\-  |  collected from private organizations   
  
####  Identifiers 

\-  |  volunteered by each visitor   
---|---  
\-  |  collected from public records or bodies   
\-  |  collected from private organizations   
  
####  Specific Data 

\-  |  volunteered by each visitor   
---|---  
\-  |  collected from public records or bodies   
\-  |  collected from private organizations   
  
* * *

* * *
